<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Just Fun on Life Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Just Fun on Life Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ron Swanson</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/ronswanson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/ronswanson/</guid>
      <description>&#34;I know what I&#39;m about son.&#34;  Ron Swanson is the simply the best Swanson.
I watch all kinds of comedy and I love all kinds of comedy. Good comedians are great philosophers who bring out the absurdities in life. They&amp;rsquo;re great observers, great listeners, great communicators, great actors, and great thinkers.
Good comedians extract humor out of the simplest of things. Ron Swanson finds it in silence. While many comedians are loud, energetic, emphatic, expressive and do great caricature, Ron manages to be funny by not doing anything, a master of deadpan comedy, he&amp;rsquo;s the punctuation marks in the otherwise unpunctuated soliloquies of Leslie Knopes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jólabókaflóð</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/jolabokafloo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 21:15:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/jolabokafloo/</guid>
      <description>I love words.
I found this wholesome link on Reddit while I was doing some work (*cough*). As the US is riling under Mr. Pai&amp;rsquo;s proud accomplishments there are some countries that have figured it all out.
 Every year since 1944, the Icelandic book trade has published a catalogue – called Bókatíðindi (‘Book Bulletin’, in English) – that is sent to every household in the country in mid-November during the Reykjavik Book Fair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zugzwang</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/zugzwang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 12:41:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/zugzwang/</guid>
      <description>Zugzwang
 (n.) a situation in which the obligation to make a move in one&amp;rsquo;s turn is a serious, often decisive, disadvantage, often in the final years of grad school.
 Zugzywangy.
  I don&amp;rsquo;t understand music and yet I like to listen to it, same goes with girls. I recently came across this video on youtube where the guy describes chess games and it&amp;rsquo;s fun to watch even without knowing anything about chess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 12:40:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>I spent the entire day today configuring Hugo so that I can write a blog. The alternative was of course using the free, efficient, easy to use, readily configurable blog sites. What be life without a little pain?
In my college I owned a shitty Acer laptop with an utterly useless battery and a cooling system so bad that the fan would act as a noise cancelling device for the din outside.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>