<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Everglades etc. on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/posts/travel/everglades-etc./</link>
    <description>Recent content in Everglades etc. on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/posts/travel/everglades-etc./index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>After Glades</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/after-glades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/after-glades/</guid>
      <description>In conclusion I&amp;rsquo;ve spent 2 days at the Everglades, 1 day at the Biscayne National Park, 1 day at the Miami beach and 1 day mostly driving. Because of the cold coming from the storm I could not do many of the standard things but on the bright side there were no mosquitoes. I could have done a few things better but most things were out of my control, again thanks to the weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biscayne</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/biscayne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/biscayne/</guid>
      <description>My canoeing partner had mentioned the Biscayne National Park to me. Upon googling I found out that the park was right next to the Everglades and had a lot of trips that looked interesting. I was surprised that I had not come across these adventures before.
I booked my trips online (why can&amp;rsquo;t other parks allow this?). The snorkeling trip was not available here too because of the cold weather so instead I went a boat trip to a nearby island, which was pretty lame, and extremely unpleasant because of the cold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shark Valley</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/shark-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/shark-valley/</guid>
      <description>The next day I drove early morning to Shark Valley. This visitor center is at the center of what are called the historical Everglades but now it is practically the northern entrance. There is a single 15 mile biking trail at this visitor center. You can rent a bike for $9 per hour which is what I did. Along the way to Shark Valley you can see a lot of airboat tour advertisement which I was tempted to try, but because of the cold it was unlikely that I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the Glades</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/at-the-glades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/at-the-glades/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;There are no other Everglades in the world.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash;The Everglades: River of Grass 
 I woke up at 5:45am, determined to make the most out of the first day of the year. It was dark and hazy outside when I started heading towards the Everglades on US-1. As you exit US-1 the traffic starts dwindling until you reach a long single lane street passing through the massive lush green South Floridian agricultural lands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Before Glades</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/before-glades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/before-glades/</guid>
      <description>Already my friends are posting new year wishes on facebook, in the first half of the world the calendars have been renewed and a nascent year has taken it&amp;rsquo;s first breath.
 Sunset at BWI   I&amp;rsquo;m watching the planes take off at the Baltimore airport against the setting sun, the morning snow is still littered on the ground making half the hanger appear white.
My plane has elegantly attached itself to the gate, like a peck on the cheek.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>