<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fiction on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fiction on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphic Novels</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/graphic-novels/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/graphic-novels/</guid>
      <description>HBO is bringing out a remixed version of the Watchmen and it brings back some very fond memories.
When I first saw Zack Snyder&amp;rsquo;s Watchmen I had never heard of Alan Moore or Neil Gaiman. I had seen Snyder&amp;rsquo;s flashy, extreme slo-moed, over the top 300 which, if nothing else, was an enjoyable watch. I did enjoy watching Watchmen too, but unlike 300, Watchmen was a revolutionary movie for me as it introduced me to the genre of graphic novels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rereading Sherlock Holmes</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/rereading-sherlock-holmes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/rereading-sherlock-holmes/</guid>
      <description>Sherlock Holmes was perhaps one of the first non-school books I have ever read. My first books were goosebumps, nancy drew, hardy boys and then I graduated to Sherlock Holmes and LOTR.
I mostly read Sherlock in the summer, when I would have a lot of free time and would often be traveling to see my extended family in the hot and sunny rural India, where there would be no electricity and no TV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast for Champions</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/breakfast-for-champions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/breakfast-for-champions/</guid>
      <description>&#34;As I approached my fiftieth birthday, I had become more and more enraged and mystified by the idiot decisions made by my countrymen. And then I had come suddenly to pity them, for I understood how innocent and natural it was for them to behave so abominably, and with such abominable results: They were doing their best to live like people invented in story books. This was the reason Americans shot each other so often: It was a convenient literary device for ending short stories and books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Remains of the Day</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/remains-of-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/remains-of-the-day/</guid>
      <description>“One must wait until the evening to see how splendid the day has been.” - Sophocles
 Oh man, what do I say about this novel? It was excruciating to keep reading it, perhaps for something like 90% of the novel my mental state was somewhere between mildly frustrated and benignly annoyed. But I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I persisted and finished the damn thing.
The story is narrated by a butler, a Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Station Eleven</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/station-eleven/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/station-eleven/</guid>
      <description>Survival is insufficient, is what it says on the lead caravan of the Traveling Symphony, a group of actors and musicians traversing the treacherous post-Georgian-Flu world which has wiped out most of humanity and destroyed the human civilization leaving behind scattered towns and technological relics.
Station Eleven jumps across three timelines - pre, post, and during the apocalypse - following the lives of three people who by a chance of fate are brought together momentarily and whose lives then diverge into the past and the future along a fragile web, their stories bursting out of a single moment in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Let Me Go</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/never-let-me-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/never-let-me-go/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I keep thinking about this river somewhere, with the water moving really fast. And these two people in the water, trying to hold onto each other, holding on as hard as they can, but in the end it&amp;rsquo;s just too much. The current&amp;rsquo;s too strong. They&amp;rsquo;ve got to let go, drift apart.&amp;rdquo;
- Never Let Me Go
 Ishiguro is a Japanese author brought up in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norwegian Wood</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/norwegian-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/norwegian-wood/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What happens when people open their hearts?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;They get better.” - Norwegian Wood
 Norwegian Wood is a teenage love story/coming of age story set mainly in Tokyo and the mountains of Kyoto. The name derives from the eponymous song by the Beatles.
I have very mixed feelings about the book. On one hand, the book has a very pulp feeling to it. There are too many sex scenes described with unnecessary details (the scenes aren&amp;rsquo;t even interesting, just teenagers jerking each other off) and every conversation between the protagonists eventually converges towards sex, love, and masturbation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>