<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>advice on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/advice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in advice on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving a Math Talk</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/maths-science/teaching/giving-a-math-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/maths-science/teaching/giving-a-math-talk/</guid>
      <description>I recently saw this fun video about the tension between clarity and mystery and the role of this tension in creating good design. It made me think about giving a math talk.
I think this element is often neglected when one prepares a math class or just a math talk.
It is understood that unlike, say, in fiction, mystery is inevitable and undesirable in mathematics. While it is good to have a bunch of unsolved problems to work on, we would very much like to know the answers to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hails on a Plane</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/hails-on-a-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/hails-on-a-plane/</guid>
      <description>It is quite an everyday thing to be stuck in a plane on the tarmac at the Denver airport awaiting it&amp;rsquo;s turn to get on the runway. It is, however, not an everyday thing to have your plane bombarded by huge hailstones while it is there. At first it sounds like some firecrackers are going off in a distance, until you listen closely and realize that the sounds are coming from all over the plane, until finally you look out of the window to witness the scary sight of hail rendering your plane incapable of flying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symmetries &amp; Polynomials</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/maths-science/teaching/symmetries-polynomials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/maths-science/teaching/symmetries-polynomials/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;In the broad light of day mathematicians check their equations and their proofs, leaving no stone unturned in their search for rigour. But, at night, under the full moon, they dream, they float among the stars and wonder at the miracle of the heavens. They are inspired. Without dreams there is no art, no mathematics, no life.&amp;rdquo; -Michael Atiyah
 I finally finished my week long class on the ideas behind Galois&amp;rsquo; proof of why a quintic cannot be solved using radicals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>