<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathcamp on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mathcamp on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hails on a Plane</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/hails-on-a-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/hails-on-a-plane/</guid>
      <description>It is quite an everyday thing to be stuck in a plane on the tarmac at the Denver airport awaiting it&amp;rsquo;s turn to get on the runway. It is, however, not an everyday thing to have your plane bombarded by huge hailstones while it is there. At first it sounds like some firecrackers are going off in a distance, until you listen closely and realize that the sounds are coming from all over the plane, until finally you look out of the window to witness the scary sight of hail rendering your plane incapable of flying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye 2018</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/goodbye-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/goodbye-2018/</guid>
      <description>It is my last afternoon in Golden, CO. I&amp;rsquo;m sitting by a window in a café in the small downtown, staring out at the clouded skies, at the still air and the gently moving leaves.
Tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;ll head out from here and move over to another world. A part of me will stay back in Golden, watching the sun rise from beyond the rocks, lingering in the dorms and the classrooms and will get replaced with something different, hopefully better; and as the memory of all that we were fades, we&amp;rsquo;ll move on building our lives with the bonds we&amp;rsquo;ve created and the friendships we&amp;rsquo;ve made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parking Lots</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/parking-lot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/parking-lot/</guid>
      <description>It was the last day of the camp. All the campers were leaving out in busses and cars, being chaperoned off by the staff to the airport at various times during the day. As had been normal for quite a few days now (or was it weeks?), I had slept for 5-6 hours the previous night and yet was wide awake for my driving shifts.
In a comedy of errors, in the morning I had dropped a camper off whose parents had completely bungled up the departure plan.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>