<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>backpacking on Life Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/backpacking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in backpacking on Life Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/backpacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Rock</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/arch-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/arch-rock/</guid>
      <description>Located on the Fern Lake trail this campground is adjacent to a large pile of rocks, hence the name. Located far away from the paved road, the trailhead is itself quite mysterious and severely lacking in signage. Everything about the campsite was rocky which unfortunately made taking a dump a bit difficult and requiring some ingenuity.
As there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much to do here thanks to the rocks, we decided to go on a dawn hike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boulder Brook</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/boulderbrook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/boulderbrook/</guid>
      <description>Of all my outdoors experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve perhaps never felt as alarmed as one evening in the Rockies.
 We woke up to find the entire world shrouded in a thin layer of mist and rain. As for the sun, not even a faint outline was visible anywhere. The first event to throw a wrench in our perfectly planned trip was the breaking down of our gas stove. No matter what the stove just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chisos Mountains</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/chisos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/chisos/</guid>
      <description>I reached the Chisos Visitor Center at 5, the place is nearly 5 hours from the nearby Midland airport. I had to hike up the Laguna Meadows trail and part of the Colima trail in 3 hours to avoid hiking in the dark, in order to join my friends camping at Colima 3.
This wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best idea I have ever had. Turns out distances look deceptively small on a map and with 2 days worth of supplies on your back every feet of elevation hurts and every switchback decimates you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>