<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rockies on Life Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rockies on Life Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Rock</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/arch-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/arch-rock/</guid>
      <description>Located on the Fern Lake trail this campground is adjacent to a large pile of rocks, hence the name. Located far away from the paved road, the trailhead is itself quite mysterious and severely lacking in signage. Everything about the campsite was rocky which unfortunately made taking a dump a bit difficult and requiring some ingenuity.
As there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much to do here thanks to the rocks, we decided to go on a dawn hike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RMNP Campgrounds</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/campgrounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/campgrounds/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I had hiked in the Rockies in the Indian Peaks Park up to the Blue Lakes. It was more of a walk than a hike. 
Now we were headed to the Rocky Mountain National Park for four days of camping and backpacking. The Rockies themselves span thousands of miles in the US and Canada, and the Rocky Mountain National Park itself covers just a small portion of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boulder Brook</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/boulderbrook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/boulderbrook/</guid>
      <description>Of all my outdoors experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve perhaps never felt as alarmed as one evening in the Rockies.
 We woke up to find the entire world shrouded in a thin layer of mist and rain. As for the sun, not even a faint outline was visible anywhere. The first event to throw a wrench in our perfectly planned trip was the breaking down of our gas stove. No matter what the stove just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t light.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>