<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bird by Bird</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/bird-by-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/bird-by-bird/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t have much truth to express unless we have gone into those rooms and closets and woods and abysses that we were told not go in to. When we have gone in and looked around for a long while, just breathing and finally taking it in &amp;ndash; then we will be able to speak in our own voice and to stay in the present moment. And that moment is home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Checklist Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/checklist-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/checklist-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Man is fallible, but maybe men are less so.&#34; -The Checklist Manifesto  It is such a simple idea, and yet so hard to follow. When your work is complicated, involves serious teamwork, needs to be done in a time critical manner, is prone to errors of oversight; make a checklist. Follow it diligently, and upgrade it frequently. The purpose of a checklist is not to replace human thought, but to take care of the trivialities so that the mind can focus on more important things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Remains of the Day</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/remains-of-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/remains-of-the-day/</guid>
      <description>“One must wait until the evening to see how splendid the day has been.” - Sophocles
 Oh man, what do I say about this novel? It was excruciating to keep reading it, perhaps for something like 90% of the novel my mental state was somewhere between mildly frustrated and benignly annoyed. But I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I persisted and finished the damn thing.
The story is narrated by a butler, a Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Station Eleven</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/station-eleven/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/station-eleven/</guid>
      <description>Survival is insufficient, is what it says on the lead caravan of the Traveling Symphony, a group of actors and musicians traversing the treacherous post-Georgian-Flu world which has wiped out most of humanity and destroyed the human civilization leaving behind scattered towns and technological relics.
Station Eleven jumps across three timelines - pre, post, and during the apocalypse - following the lives of three people who by a chance of fate are brought together momentarily and whose lives then diverge into the past and the future along a fragile web, their stories bursting out of a single moment in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Let Me Go</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/never-let-me-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/never-let-me-go/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I keep thinking about this river somewhere, with the water moving really fast. And these two people in the water, trying to hold onto each other, holding on as hard as they can, but in the end it&amp;rsquo;s just too much. The current&amp;rsquo;s too strong. They&amp;rsquo;ve got to let go, drift apart.&amp;rdquo;
- Never Let Me Go
 Ishiguro is a Japanese author brought up in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norwegian Wood</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/norwegian-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/norwegian-wood/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What happens when people open their hearts?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;They get better.” - Norwegian Wood
 Norwegian Wood is a teenage love story/coming of age story set mainly in Tokyo and the mountains of Kyoto. The name derives from the eponymous song by the Beatles.
I have very mixed feelings about the book. On one hand, the book has a very pulp feeling to it. There are too many sex scenes described with unnecessary details (the scenes aren&amp;rsquo;t even interesting, just teenagers jerking each other off) and every conversation between the protagonists eventually converges towards sex, love, and masturbation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Area of Darkness</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/an-area-of-darkness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/an-area-of-darkness/</guid>
      <description>An Area of Darkness is a disturbing pessimistic novel written by V.S. Naipaul about his first visit to India in 1962. This was India not too long after the Independence with it&amp;rsquo;s freshly minted Constitution, trying to make a transition from an English past to an Indian future. Naipaul shares the sentiments of West, the tone of the book is not unlike Slumdog Millionaire (a very unpopular movie in India).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>