<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Body Problem</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/three-body-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/three-body-problem/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Weakness and ignorance are not barriers to survival, but arrogance is.&#34; -Three Body Problem  Of the Three Body Problem trilogy, I immensely enjoyed reading the first book and had to drag my way across the other two.
The first book has a very beautiful structure. It is intensely gripping with very honest, well-formed characters, it jumps across various timelines introducing us to the Chinese cultural revolution along the way, has a whodunit mystery, creates great sci-fi worlds - a complete package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuromancer</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/neuromancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/neuromancer/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The sky above the port was the color of television, tuned to a dead channel.&#34; -Neuromancer  I always knew that The Matrix had to have found it&amp;rsquo;s concepts from some book, it was too revolutionary a movie to have spawned out of nothing. And I finally found it - Neuromancer, the archetypal cyberpunk novel.
This is probably the hardest and simultaneously the most riveting sci-fi novel I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rendezvous with Rama</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/rendezvous-with-rama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/rendezvous-with-rama/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The human race has to live with its conscience. Whatever the Hermians argue, survival is not everything.&#34; -Rendezvous with Rama  I&amp;rsquo;m biased towards space novels. Reading about space travel and stars and planets and contemplating the huge vastness and emptiness always fills me with a sense of indescribable wonder, bliss, and humility.
Arthur Clarke&amp;rsquo;s Rendezvous with Rama is a space poetry. It starts with a simple premise of an alien object (Rama) suddenly appearing in the solar system and humans venturing out to explore it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast for Champions</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/breakfast-for-champions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/breakfast-for-champions/</guid>
      <description>&#34;As I approached my fiftieth birthday, I had become more and more enraged and mystified by the idiot decisions made by my countrymen. And then I had come suddenly to pity them, for I understood how innocent and natural it was for them to behave so abominably, and with such abominable results: They were doing their best to live like people invented in story books. This was the reason Americans shot each other so often: It was a convenient literary device for ending short stories and books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gods Themselves</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/the-gods-themselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/the-gods-themselves/</guid>
      <description>In the opening scene of Nolan&amp;rsquo;s Prestige, Michael Caine explains what a magic trick consists of - a pledge, a turn, and the hardest part - the Prestige. This is what Asimov&amp;rsquo;s stories are like. He starts with an ordinary world with something slightly extraordinary about it, takes you around on a tour through the wonders of the world to distract you and slowly builds up the mystery in plain sight, until the big reveal in the final act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bird by Bird</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/bird-by-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/bird-by-bird/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t have much truth to express unless we have gone into those rooms and closets and woods and abysses that we were told not go in to. When we have gone in and looked around for a long while, just breathing and finally taking it in &amp;ndash; then we will be able to speak in our own voice and to stay in the present moment. And that moment is home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Checklist Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/checklist-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/checklist-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Man is fallible, but maybe men are less so.&#34; -The Checklist Manifesto  It is such a simple idea, and yet so hard to follow. When your work is complicated, involves serious teamwork, needs to be done in a time critical manner, is prone to errors of oversight; make a checklist. Follow it diligently, and upgrade it frequently. The purpose of a checklist is not to replace human thought, but to take care of the trivialities so that the mind can focus on more important things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Remains of the Day</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/remains-of-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/remains-of-the-day/</guid>
      <description>“One must wait until the evening to see how splendid the day has been.” - Sophocles
 Oh man, what do I say about this novel? It was excruciating to keep reading it, perhaps for something like 90% of the novel my mental state was somewhere between mildly frustrated and benignly annoyed. But I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I persisted and finished the damn thing.
The story is narrated by a butler, a Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Station Eleven</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/station-eleven/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/station-eleven/</guid>
      <description>Survival is insufficient, is what it says on the lead caravan of the Traveling Symphony, a group of actors and musicians traversing the treacherous post-Georgian-Flu world which has wiped out most of humanity and destroyed the human civilization leaving behind scattered towns and technological relics.
Station Eleven jumps across three timelines - pre, post, and during the apocalypse - following the lives of three people who by a chance of fate are brought together momentarily and whose lives then diverge into the past and the future along a fragile web, their stories bursting out of a single moment in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Let Me Go</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/never-let-me-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/never-let-me-go/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I keep thinking about this river somewhere, with the water moving really fast. And these two people in the water, trying to hold onto each other, holding on as hard as they can, but in the end it&amp;rsquo;s just too much. The current&amp;rsquo;s too strong. They&amp;rsquo;ve got to let go, drift apart.&amp;rdquo;
- Never Let Me Go
 Ishiguro is a Japanese author brought up in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/gtd-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/gtd-method/</guid>
      <description>These are some notes I took from the book Getting Things Done by David Allen. Let me first start with the cons of the book. First the book is tediously repetitive, while some repetition is good to drill the concepts deep in your mind, the book overdoes it. Second, the book is clearly intended for people who&amp;rsquo;ve white collar jobs, mostly managers and executives.
But that does not mean that you cannot gatecrash the party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norwegian Wood</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/norwegian-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/norwegian-wood/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What happens when people open their hearts?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;They get better.” - Norwegian Wood
 Norwegian Wood is a teenage love story/coming of age story set mainly in Tokyo and the mountains of Kyoto. The name derives from the eponymous song by the Beatles.
I have very mixed feelings about the book. On one hand, the book has a very pulp feeling to it. There are too many sex scenes described with unnecessary details (the scenes aren&amp;rsquo;t even interesting, just teenagers jerking each other off) and every conversation between the protagonists eventually converges towards sex, love, and masturbation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Area of Darkness</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/an-area-of-darkness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/an-area-of-darkness/</guid>
      <description>An Area of Darkness is a disturbing pessimistic novel written by V.S. Naipaul about his first visit to India in 1962. This was India not too long after the Independence with it&amp;rsquo;s freshly minted Constitution, trying to make a transition from an English past to an Indian future. Naipaul shares the sentiments of West, the tone of the book is not unlike Slumdog Millionaire (a very unpopular movie in India).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking, Fast &amp; Slow</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/the-two-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 12:40:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/the-two-systems/</guid>
      <description>Thinking, Fast and Slow in a life changing book written by our lord and savior Daniel Kahneman, Danny Kanny.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read this book you should drop everything that you&amp;rsquo;re doing and start reading it right away. It is extremely well written and easy to read, with short chapters and lucid Hemingway-styled language lacking any pretentiousness.
Danny Kanny posits a two system model for our minds. The faster system which is also the system truly in charge, Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>