<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Camping on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/camping/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Camping on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/camping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RMNP Campgrounds</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/campgrounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/campgrounds/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I had hiked in the Rockies in the Indian Peaks Park up to the Blue Lakes. It was more of a walk than a hike. 
Now we were headed to the Rocky Mountain National Park for four days of camping and backpacking. The Rockies themselves span thousands of miles in the US and Canada, and the Rocky Mountain National Park itself covers just a small portion of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rio Grande</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/rio-grande/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/rio-grande/</guid>
      <description>Unless you&amp;rsquo;re a pro, it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to backpack for multiple days in the Big Bend. The desert conditions require you to carry all the water you need with you and you reach your limitations really fast.
But, there are plenty other ways to appreciate the Big Bend. I car camped at the Nine Point Draw and Stillwell for one night each, and then camped on the campgrounds at Chisos and Rio Grande Village for one night each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chisos Mountains</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/chisos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/chisos/</guid>
      <description>I reached the Chisos Visitor Center at 5, the place is nearly 5 hours from the nearby Midland airport. I had to hike up the Laguna Meadows trail and part of the Colima trail in 3 hours to avoid hiking in the dark, in order to join my friends camping at Colima 3.
This wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best idea I have ever had. Turns out distances look deceptively small on a map and with 2 days worth of supplies on your back every feet of elevation hurts and every switchback decimates you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Night in the Desert</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/last-night-in-the-desert/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/last-night-in-the-desert/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What do we leave behind when we cross each frontier? Each moment seems split in two: melancholy for what was left behind and the excitement of entering a new land.&amp;rdquo; - The Motorcycle Diaries
 
I&amp;rsquo;m profoundly sad about leaving this desert. Sitting in an Indian campsite, here&amp;rsquo;s a genuine Indian looking back at a week of toiling in the Big Bend.
  It was windy a while ago, but the wind has now abated, my tent no longer dances.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>