<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>comedy on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/comedy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in comedy on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/comedy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Night Is Short, Walk on Girl</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/night-is-short-walk-on-girl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/night-is-short-walk-on-girl/</guid>
      <description>What? Is? This? Movie?
Imagine watching the climax of a Charlie Chaplin or a Three Stooges movie as a kid; people are running helter-skelter all over the place, things get so chaotic that you have no idea as to what is going on, your eyes are constantly jumping from one character to another unable to keep up with the ongoing chaos; and yet you are on the edge of your seat with a foolishly wide grin stuck to your face which stubbornly refuses to shut, and it&amp;rsquo;s only when dust settles and you sink back into your seat bursting out uncontrollably laughing that you realize you had forgotten to breathe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isle of Dogs</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/isle-of-dogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/isle-of-dogs/</guid>
      <description>I always wonder what exactly is the world that Wes Anderson sees, does he really see things the way he portrays them in his movies? What a great gift to have, I&amp;rsquo;m so envious!
Like all other Wes Anderson movies, Isle of Dogs makes no pretense of being serious or dark in any way. At the very start, there is a narrator who announces that this is a tale and introduces the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paddington 2</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/paddington-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/paddington-2/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen Paddington, and frankly the only reason I decided to watch Paddington 2 is because of it&amp;rsquo;s insanely high ratings on Rotten Tomatoes.
The ratings are not exaggerated. This is a beautifully made movie, everything about this movie is good.
  I&amp;rsquo;ll only say this, watching this movie is not unlike reading a Harry Potter book (Hagrid is in the movie!). The story is tactfully written, as if by Rowling herself, but much more cheerful, without any hint of an underlying sadness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jumanji</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/jumanji/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 23:30:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/jumanji/</guid>
      <description>Goo watch Jumanji. I&amp;rsquo;ve now become a fan of Kevin Hart after watching this movie. There is no sarcasm, no deadpan humor, nothing vulgar, nothing GTA-Hangover style, nobody ever makes fun of anybody else, all the humor is benignly self-deprecating. It&amp;rsquo;s a heartwarming, wholesome, adventurous, gripping, innocent movie. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure nobody says fuck or shit in the movie even once. And it&amp;rsquo;s still funny. I know! Who would have thought?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>