<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life@jhu on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life@jhu on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike Party</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/bike-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/bike-party/</guid>
      <description>A cultured friend of fine, who owns an expensive Brompton Bike, once told me before moving out of Baltimore that the thing that he was going to miss the most about this city was the Baltimore Bike Party. Now, this is someone who I imagine brushes his teeth while listening to E-minor sonatas and who knows the difference between a lawn and a garden, not the kind of person who makes recommendations frivolously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eye Test</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/eye-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/eye-test/</guid>
      <description>I have had glasses ever since I was 10 years old. As a kid I used to wear really thick durable plastic frames, which evolved to metal frames in my teenage years, and then back to durable plastic frames in college. My power used to increase incessantly until I stopped growing and so I&amp;rsquo;ve probably paid a visit to an ophthalmologist every single year of my life in India. Today for the first time I went for an eye check-up in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boltbus</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/boltbus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/boltbus/</guid>
      <description>Boltbus, or as I like to call it capitalism on wheels.
I&amp;rsquo;ve bought a Boltbus ticket for $1 and I&amp;rsquo;ve bought one for $70, I bet there are derivatives being traded on these ticket prices. But all in all it&amp;rsquo;s always a pleasant ride, you know why? Because there&amp;rsquo;s a toilet on the bus. In India when you travel by buses you have to schedule each one your leaks and dumps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Snow</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/first-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 13:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/first-snow/</guid>
      <description>Saturdays are the hardest for me, I have an early morning yoga class. And so every Saturday morning there is almost always an intense battle between the sleep-a-little-more and the get-your-ass-up factions. Both sides have fairly convincing arguments and the debate turns deeply philosophical pretty quickly. Fortunately the get-your-ass-up faction always wins as by then I&amp;rsquo;m wide awake and can&amp;rsquo;t possibly go back to sleep. Nice strategy!
As I stumble outside half asleep half awake trying to make it in time, I&amp;rsquo;m pleasantly surprised by the small aimlessly drifting snow flakes, taking their time dancing in the wind before melting away on the wet pavement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/hubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 14:21:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/hubble/</guid>
      <description>One of the perks of being at Hopkins is that ever so often you get to visit the Hubble Space Telescope building. It is a stolid building perched atop a small slope on the fringe of the campus overlooking a dense park through which flows calmly a small ravine, or a run, as we like to call it in this part of the world.
There isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly much to see here, the telescope being in outer Space and all that, but there is a friendly cafeteria with large glass windows serving Central American food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Parade</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/christmas-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 14:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/christmas-parade/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m usually very reluctant to try new places. I do enjoy the places AFTER I&amp;rsquo;ve been to them, the trouble lies with the planning phase. While there are several reviews available online none of them talk about, for example, how long does it take to get to Hopkins from the place? Or how sunny does it get at 3pm on a Sunday in December? None of the reviews, in short, provide any useful information to a graduate student.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>