<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Professional Assholes on Life Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/professional-assholes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Professional Assholes on Life Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/professional-assholes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/professional-assholes/apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/professional-assholes/apple/</guid>
      <description>Never buy an Apple product which is not in stock. I made this mistake and it took over a month to get this Macbook Air and its not even the greatest model in the world. This would have been fine had they told me it was going to take a month to get the laptop, but instead every 3-4 days they would send me an email saying that for certain unforeseeable reasons the shipment is delayed but you should expect to get it real soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active.com</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/professional-assholes/active_com/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/professional-assholes/active_com/</guid>
      <description>There is an official page on Active.com about what an unidentified charge of $79.95 on your bank statement means. How many such websites have you seen in your life? Here is a website that deceptively charges you hoping that you&amp;rsquo;re stupid enough to not check your credit card statement. Apparently, Active.com is one of the most successful marathon event registration website and it is popular even though this scam is extremely well known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Visa</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/professional-assholes/canadian-visa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/professional-assholes/canadian-visa/</guid>
      <description>EDIT: Heeding my (and undoubtedly) infinitely many other complaints, the Canadian embassy has changed their agency from CIC to VFS who are genuinely good at their job. No complaints anymore.
Being an Indian means that I&amp;rsquo;ve to apply for a visa even for short visits when traveling internationally. This is usually a small loss of money and time and I&amp;rsquo;ve never had any trouble with this process. That was until I applied for a Canadian visa in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>