<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rendezvous with Rama</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/rendezvous-with-rama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/rendezvous-with-rama/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The human race has to live with its conscience. Whatever the Hermians argue, survival is not everything.&#34; -Rendezvous with Rama  I&amp;rsquo;m biased towards space novels. Reading about space travel and stars and planets and contemplating the huge vastness and emptiness always fills me with a sense of indescribable wonder, bliss, and humility.
Arthur Clarke&amp;rsquo;s Rendezvous with Rama is a space poetry. It starts with a simple premise of an alien object (Rama) suddenly appearing in the solar system and humans venturing out to explore it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hails on a Plane</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/hails-on-a-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/hails-on-a-plane/</guid>
      <description>It is quite an everyday thing to be stuck in a plane on the tarmac at the Denver airport awaiting it&amp;rsquo;s turn to get on the runway. It is, however, not an everyday thing to have your plane bombarded by huge hailstones while it is there. At first it sounds like some firecrackers are going off in a distance, until you listen closely and realize that the sounds are coming from all over the plane, until finally you look out of the window to witness the scary sight of hail rendering your plane incapable of flying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye 2018</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/goodbye-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/goodbye-2018/</guid>
      <description>It is my last afternoon in Golden, CO. I&amp;rsquo;m sitting by a window in a café in the small downtown, staring out at the clouded skies, at the still air and the gently moving leaves.
Tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;ll head out from here and move over to another world. A part of me will stay back in Golden, watching the sun rise from beyond the rocks, lingering in the dorms and the classrooms and will get replaced with something different, hopefully better; and as the memory of all that we were fades, we&amp;rsquo;ll move on building our lives with the bonds we&amp;rsquo;ve created and the friendships we&amp;rsquo;ve made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast for Champions</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/breakfast-for-champions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/breakfast-for-champions/</guid>
      <description>&#34;As I approached my fiftieth birthday, I had become more and more enraged and mystified by the idiot decisions made by my countrymen. And then I had come suddenly to pity them, for I understood how innocent and natural it was for them to behave so abominably, and with such abominable results: They were doing their best to live like people invented in story books. This was the reason Americans shot each other so often: It was a convenient literary device for ending short stories and books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serendipity</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/serendipity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/serendipity/</guid>
      <description>We were sitting at the far end of the pub, tired, exhausted, and relieved. I was slowly wiping the water that had condensed on the glass of my IPA with my fingertips, or was it a Belgian? We had conjoined two adjacent tables. The pub was playing some recent-old pop music, as usual. The lights were dim and yellow, there were television screens tucked in every corner airing sports to give people something to look at between conversations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gods Themselves</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/the-gods-themselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/the-gods-themselves/</guid>
      <description>In the opening scene of Nolan&amp;rsquo;s Prestige, Michael Caine explains what a magic trick consists of - a pledge, a turn, and the hardest part - the Prestige. This is what Asimov&amp;rsquo;s stories are like. He starts with an ordinary world with something slightly extraordinary about it, takes you around on a tour through the wonders of the world to distract you and slowly builds up the mystery in plain sight, until the big reveal in the final act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active.com</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/professional-assholes/active_com/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/professional-assholes/active_com/</guid>
      <description>There is an official page on Active.com about what an unidentified charge of $79.95 on your bank statement means. How many such websites have you seen in your life? Here is a website that deceptively charges you hoping that you&amp;rsquo;re stupid enough to not check your credit card statement. Apparently, Active.com is one of the most successful marathon event registration website and it is popular even though this scam is extremely well known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Visa</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/professional-assholes/canadian-visa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/professional-assholes/canadian-visa/</guid>
      <description>Being an Indian means that I&amp;rsquo;ve to apply for a visa even for short visits when travelling internationally. This is usually a small loss of money and time and I&amp;rsquo;ve never had any trouble with this process. That was until I applied for a Canadian visa in the US.
The Canadian government (fucking idiots) has outsourced the visa application process to a third party. These people are fucking morons incapable of making a sensible website and having the most arcane methods of application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bird by Bird</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/bird-by-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/bird-by-bird/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t have much truth to express unless we have gone into those rooms and closets and woods and abysses that we were told not go in to. When we have gone in and looked around for a long while, just breathing and finally taking it in &amp;ndash; then we will be able to speak in our own voice and to stay in the present moment. And that moment is home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike Party</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/bike-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/bike-party/</guid>
      <description>A cultured friend of fine, who owns an expensive Brompton Bike, once told me before moving out of Baltimore that the thing that he was going to miss the most about this city was the Baltimore Bike Party. Now, this is someone who I imagine brushes his teeth while listening to E-minor sonatas and who knows the difference between a lawn and a garden, not the kind of person who makes recommendations frivolously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isle of Dogs</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/isle-of-dogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/isle-of-dogs/</guid>
      <description>I always wonder what exactly is the world that Wes Anderson sees, does he really see things the way he portrays them in his movies? What a great gift to have, I&amp;rsquo;m so envious!
Like all other Wes Anderson movies, Isle of Dogs makes no pretense of being serious or dark in any way. At the very start, there is a narrator who announces that this is a tale and introduces the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rio Grande</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/rio-grande/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/rio-grande/</guid>
      <description>Unless you&amp;rsquo;re a pro, it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to backpack for multiple days in the Big Bend. The desert conditions require you to carry all the water you need with you and you reach your limitations really fast.
But, there are plenty other ways to appreciate the Big Bend. I car camped at the Nine Point Draw and Stillwell for one night each, and then camped on the campgrounds at Chisos and Rio Grande Village for one night each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chisos Mountains</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/chisos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/chisos/</guid>
      <description>I reached the Chisos Visitor Center at 5, the place is nearly 5 hours from the nearby Midland airport. I had to hike up the Laguna Meadows trail and part of the Colima trail in 3 hours to avoid hiking in the dark, in order to join my friends camping at Colima 3.
This wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best idea I have ever had. Turns out distances look deceptively small on a map and with 2 days worth of supplies on your back every feet of elevation hurts and every switchback decimates you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chisos Mountains</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/chisos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/rockies/chisos/</guid>
      <description>I reached the Chisos Visitor Center at 5, the place is nearly 5 hours from the nearby Midland airport. I had to hike up the Laguna Meadows trail and part of the Colima trail in 3 hours to avoid hiking in the dark, in order to join my friends camping at Colima 3.
This wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best idea I have ever had. Turns out distances look deceptively small on a map and with 2 days worth of supplies on your back every feet of elevation hurts and every switchback decimates you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Night in the Desert</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/last-night-in-the-desert/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/big-bend/last-night-in-the-desert/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What do we leave behind when we cross each frontier? Each moment seems split in two: melancholy for what was left behind and the excitement of entering a new land.&amp;rdquo; - The Motorcycle Diaries
 
I&amp;rsquo;m profoundly sad about leaving this desert. Sitting in an Indian campsite, here&amp;rsquo;s a genuine Indian looking back at a week of toiling in the Big Bend.
  It was windy a while ago, but the wind has now abated, my tent no longer dances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Checklist Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/checklist-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/checklist-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Man is fallible, but maybe men are less so.&#34; -The Checklist Manifesto  It is such a simple idea, and yet so hard to follow. When your work is complicated, involves serious teamwork, needs to be done in a time critical manner, is prone to errors of oversight; make a checklist. Follow it diligently, and upgrade it frequently. The purpose of a checklist is not to replace human thought, but to take care of the trivialities so that the mind can focus on more important things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief History of Time</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/maths--science/popular-science/brief-history-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/maths--science/popular-science/brief-history-of-time/</guid>
      <description>Someone had gifted me this book as a kid, I do not remember who or when, I think it was my maths teacher.
I remember Hawking says in his book, that adding equations to books decreases their popularity. I remember not particularly liking this.
But I also remember reading, for the first time in my life, about light cones, about causality, about the big bang, black holes and their event horizons, entropy and the arrow of time, about Hubble&amp;rsquo;s discovery, the multitude of galaxies and the ever expanding universe, about the electrons with their dual natures and their half spins, bosons and fermions, Heisenberg&amp;rsquo;s uncertainty principle, Pauli&amp;rsquo;s exclusion principle, about supernovas and the creation of heavy elements, the spinning neutron stars, the Chandrasekhar limit, the spontaneous creation and annihilation of particles, the Hawking radiation, about quarks and their funny color names, about gluons, about the strong and weak nuclear forces, radioactivity, mesons, and muons, and pions, about quasars and gamma rays, about relativity and the space-time, the precession of mercury, the ultraviolet catastrophe, Einstein&amp;rsquo;s genius, about his folly, about mass and energy, the Planck&amp;rsquo;s constant, about gravitational lensing, about strings, about mirrors, about the vastness of the universe, and our place in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parking Lots</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/parking-lot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/mathcamp/parking-lot/</guid>
      <description>It was the last day of the camp. All the campers were leaving out in busses and cars, being chaperoned off by the staff to the airport at various times during the day. As had been normal for quite a few days now (or was it weeks?), I had slept for 5-6 hours the previous night and yet was wide awake for my driving shifts.
In a comedy of errors, in the morning I had dropped a camper off whose parents had completely bungled up the departure plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy of Running</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/stray-thoughts/joy-of-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/stray-thoughts/joy-of-running/</guid>
      <description>The running high is like having a prolonged orgasm.
I have a love-hate relationship with running. At the core of it, it is an extremely repetitive act, you&amp;rsquo;re doing one thing and one thing only, but then it is this simplicity of action that puts you in a trance. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the time before you start running and the time at the beginning of the run are excruciating, there is just no rational reason to subject yourself to such a monotonous ordeal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Remains of the Day</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/remains-of-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/remains-of-the-day/</guid>
      <description>“One must wait until the evening to see how splendid the day has been.” - Sophocles
 Oh man, what do I say about this novel? It was excruciating to keep reading it, perhaps for something like 90% of the novel my mental state was somewhere between mildly frustrated and benignly annoyed. But I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I persisted and finished the damn thing.
The story is narrated by a butler, a Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Station Eleven</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/station-eleven/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/station-eleven/</guid>
      <description>Survival is insufficient, is what it says on the lead caravan of the Traveling Symphony, a group of actors and musicians traversing the treacherous post-Georgian-Flu world which has wiped out most of humanity and destroyed the human civilization leaving behind scattered towns and technological relics.
Station Eleven jumps across three timelines - pre, post, and during the apocalypse - following the lives of three people who by a chance of fate are brought together momentarily and whose lives then diverge into the past and the future along a fragile web, their stories bursting out of a single moment in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Thyself</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/know-thyself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/know-thyself/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important lessons of Thinking, Fast and Slow is that our brains are unable to analyze real world data objectively. We alter our memories and retroactively modify our experiences to fit a story. The only solution to this is to keep records and to trust the data.
For me, the two most easily measurable resources are internet usage and money. After reading the book I was sure I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being honest with myself about these things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blank Spaces</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/stray-thoughts/blank-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/stray-thoughts/blank-spaces/</guid>
      <description>When I was making this blog I fidgeted around a lot with the style, trying to make it look pretty but I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it right. Until I realized that what makes a lot of websites pretty are the blank spaces.
This is, in fact, true for almost all art forms. All good movies have those moments of stillness, all good conversations have those long spaces, most paintings have patches of featureless color, all novels have moments of long contemplation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Let Me Go</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/never-let-me-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/never-let-me-go/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I keep thinking about this river somewhere, with the water moving really fast. And these two people in the water, trying to hold onto each other, holding on as hard as they can, but in the end it&amp;rsquo;s just too much. The current&amp;rsquo;s too strong. They&amp;rsquo;ve got to let go, drift apart.&amp;rdquo;
- Never Let Me Go
 Ishiguro is a Japanese author brought up in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Dance</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/stray-thoughts/why-i-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/stray-thoughts/why-i-dance/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been spending a lot of time thinking about what I want to do with my life. Turns out this is a really hard question. The biggest difficulty is probably trying to understand what it means to do something with your life.
Right now I&amp;rsquo;m coming back from a dance meet-up with some old friends and new, a little tipsy and drinking some more, and a lot exhilarated from moving on the dance floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spoken Language</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/maths--science/popular-science/spoken-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/maths--science/popular-science/spoken-language/</guid>
      <description>I was attending the Science of Learning Symposium at JHU, which is usually quite fascinating, but was very boring this year. These are the things that frustrate me about formal events:
 People take extended time to introduce the speakers (nobody wants to hear you talk, go away). People in suits, usually senior professors who have stopped being scientists, who think they&amp;rsquo;re funny because nobody is honest to them, make shitty jokes and laugh at their own jokes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eye Test</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/eye-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/eye-test/</guid>
      <description>I have had glasses ever since I was 10 years old. As a kid I used to wear really thick durable plastic frames, which evolved to metal frames in my teenage years, and then back to durable plastic frames in college. My power used to increase incessantly until I stopped growing and so I&amp;rsquo;ve probably paid a visit to an ophthalmologist every single year of my life in India. Today for the first time I went for an eye check-up in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/gtd-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/gtd-method/</guid>
      <description>These are some notes I took from the book Getting Things Done by David Allen. Let me first start with the cons of the book. First the book is tediously repetitive, while some repetition is good to drill the concepts deep in your mind, the book overdoes it. Second, the book is clearly intended for people who&amp;rsquo;ve white collar jobs, mostly managers and executives.
But that does not mean that you cannot gatecrash the party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symmetries &amp; Polynomials</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/maths--science/teaching/symmetries--polynomials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/maths--science/teaching/symmetries--polynomials/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;In the broad light of day mathematicians check their equations and their proofs, leaving no stone unturned in their search for rigour. But, at night, under the full moon, they dream, they float among the stars and wonder at the miracle of the heavens. They are inspired. Without dreams there is no art, no mathematics, no life.&amp;rdquo; -Michael Atiyah
 I finally finished my week long class on the ideas behind Galois&amp;rsquo; proof of why a quintic cannot be solved using radicals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paddington 2</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/paddington-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/paddington-2/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen Paddington, and frankly the only reason I decided to watch Paddington 2 is because of it&amp;rsquo;s insanely high ratings on Rotten Tomatoes.
The ratings are not exaggerated. This is a beautifully made movie, everything about this movie is good.
  I&amp;rsquo;ll only say this, watching this movie is not unlike reading a Harry Potter book (Hagrid is in the movie!). The story is tactfully written, as if by Rowling herself, but much more cheerful, without any hint of an underlying sadness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Alone</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/stray-thoughts/being-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 20:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/stray-thoughts/being-alone/</guid>
      <description>I came home today from the gym all sweaty and smelly and quite content. As I threw my bags on the bed and settled down, I had a great urge to open up my laptop and check something online. Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been becoming increasing aware of this internet addiction that seems more and more unavoidable.
I resisted and just laid myself down on my bed staring at the ceiling. Perhaps for the first time I noticed how beautifully the walls of my house are painted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norwegian Wood</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/norwegian-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/norwegian-wood/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What happens when people open their hearts?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;They get better.” - Norwegian Wood
 Norwegian Wood is a teenage love story/coming of age story set mainly in Tokyo and the mountains of Kyoto. The name derives from the eponymous song by the Beatles.
I have very mixed feelings about the book. On one hand, the book has a very pulp feeling to it. There are too many sex scenes described with unnecessary details (the scenes aren&amp;rsquo;t even interesting, just teenagers jerking each other off) and every conversation between the protagonists eventually converges towards sex, love, and masturbation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shape of Water</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/shape-of-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/shape-of-water/</guid>
      <description>Guillermo del Toro&amp;rsquo;s best work is undoubtedly Pan&amp;rsquo;s Labyrinth, a bittersweet dreamlike tale of a young girl who finds herself in the unknown forests of Spain.
This new movie of his, Shape of Water, in some ways tries to recreate the same feel. The premise is completely different but the setting is exactly as in Pan&amp;rsquo;s Labyrinth. There is an unfortunate damsel with evil parents/bosses who comes in contact with magical creatures and finds an escape from &amp;ldquo;reality&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biscayne</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/everglades-etc./biscayne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/everglades-etc./biscayne/</guid>
      <description>The Biscayne National Park visitor center is by the sea of course and is at the end of a serene Biscayne boulevard. There are sailing ships and motor boats marooned at the piers and the water is pristine blue. Close to the shore are the red mangroves trees, apparently the entire Biscayne National Park was a part of the Everglades not too long ago before the water levels rose. The waters right next to the shore are slow zones because apparently manatees (which are endangered now) like to congregate here and are likely to get damaged by careless boats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shark Valley</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/everglades-etc./shark-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/everglades-etc./shark-valley/</guid>
      <description>The next day I drove early morning to Shark Valley. This visitor center is at the center of what are called the historical Everglades but now it is practically the northern entrance. There is a single 15 mile biking trail at this visitor center. You can rent a bike for $9 per hour which is what I did. Along the way to Shark Valley you can see a lot of airboat tour advertisement which I was tempted to try, but because of the cold it was unlikely that I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the Glades</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/everglades-etc./at-the-glades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/everglades-etc./at-the-glades/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;There are no other Everglades in the world.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash;The Everglades: River of Grass 
 I woke up at 5:45am, determined to make the most out of the first day of the year. It was dark and hazy outside when I started heading towards the Everglades on US-1. As you exit US-1 the traffic starts dwindling until you reach a long single lane street passing through the massive lush green South Floridian agricultural lands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Before Glades</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/everglades-etc./before-glades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/travel/everglades-etc./before-glades/</guid>
      <description>The first thing you notice upon landing in Florida is the weather. The Miami airport is very well designed BUT it lacks good markings. I could spot several other passengers getting confused over the airport direction signs and falling back onto their smartphones.
I did not have time to explore Miami tonight. I rented a car and drove over to my airbnb. The rental facility is conveniently connected to the airport by a train (San Diego should learn).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Area of Darkness</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/an-area-of-darkness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/an-area-of-darkness/</guid>
      <description>An Area of Darkness is a disturbing pessimistic novel written by V.S. Naipaul about his first visit to India in 1962. This was India not too long after the Independence with it&amp;rsquo;s freshly minted Constitution, trying to make a transition from an English past to an Indian future. Naipaul shares the sentiments of West, the tone of the book is not unlike Slumdog Millionaire (a very unpopular movie in India).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking, Fast &amp; Slow</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/the-two-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 12:40:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/the-two-systems/</guid>
      <description>Thinking, Fast and Slow in a life changing book written by our lord and savior Daniel Kahneman, Danny Kanny.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read this book you should drop everything that you&amp;rsquo;re doing and start reading it right away. It is extremely well written and easy to read, with short chapters and lucid Hemingway-styled language lacking any pretentiousness.
Danny Kanny posits a two system model for our minds. The faster system which is also the system truly in charge, Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icarus</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/icarus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/icarus/</guid>
      <description>“The choice for mankind lies between freedom and happiness and for the great bulk of mankind, happiness is better.” - 1984
Icarus is a shocking film about an American filmmaker getting accidentally intertwined with head of the Russian anti-doping lab, Rodchenkov, during the unfolding of the Russian doping scandal. It starts out with the juxtaposition of Lance Armstrong&amp;rsquo;s testimonies before and after his conviction of guilt, and that sets the tone for the rest of the film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jumanji</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/jumanji/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 23:30:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/movies/jumanji/</guid>
      <description>Goo watch Jumanji. I&amp;rsquo;ve now become a fan of Kevin Hart after watching this movie. There is no sarcasm, no deadpan humor, nothing vulgar, nothing GTA-Hangover style, nobody ever makes fun of anybody else, all the humor is benignly self-deprecating. It&amp;rsquo;s a heartwarming, wholesome, adventurous, gripping, innocent movie. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure nobody says fuck or shit in the movie even once. And it&amp;rsquo;s still funny. I know! Who would have thought?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jólabókaflóð</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/jolabokafloo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 21:15:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/jolabokafloo/</guid>
      <description>I love words.
I found this wholesome link on Reddit while I was doing some work (*cough*). As the US is riling under Mr. Pai&amp;rsquo;s proud accomplishments there are some countries that have figured it all out.
 Every year since 1944, the Icelandic book trade has published a catalogue – called Bókatíðindi (‘Book Bulletin’, in English) – that is sent to every household in the country in mid-November during the Reykjavik Book Fair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zugzwang</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/zugzwang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 12:41:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/zugzwang/</guid>
      <description>Zugzwang
 (n.) a situation in which the obligation to make a move in one&amp;rsquo;s turn is a serious, often decisive, disadvantage, often in the final years of grad school.
 Zugzywangy.
  I don&amp;rsquo;t understand music and yet I like to listen to it, same goes with girls. I recently came across this video on youtube where the guy describes chess games and it&amp;rsquo;s fun to watch even without knowing anything about chess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boltbus</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/boltbus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/boltbus/</guid>
      <description>Boltbus, or as I like to call it capitalism on wheels.
I&amp;rsquo;ve bought a Boltbus ticket for $1 and I&amp;rsquo;ve bought one for $70, I bet there are derivatives being traded on these ticket prices. But all in all it&amp;rsquo;s always a pleasant ride, you know why? Because there&amp;rsquo;s a toilet on the bus. In India when you travel by buses you have to schedule each one your leaks and dumps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Snow</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/first-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 13:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/first-snow/</guid>
      <description>Saturdays are the hardest for me, I have an early morning yoga class. And so every Saturday morning there is almost always an intense battle between the sleep-a-little-more and the get-your-ass-up factions. Both sides have fairly convincing arguments and the debate turns deeply philosophical pretty quickly. Fortunately the get-your-ass-up faction always wins as by then I&amp;rsquo;m wide awake and can&amp;rsquo;t possibly go back to sleep. Nice strategy!
As I stumble outside half asleep half awake trying to make it in time, I&amp;rsquo;m pleasantly surprised by the small aimlessly drifting snow flakes, taking their time dancing in the wind before melting away on the wet pavement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/hubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 14:21:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/hubble/</guid>
      <description>One of the perks of being at Hopkins is that ever so often you get to visit the Hubble Space Telescope building. It is a stolid building perched atop a small slope on the fringe of the campus overlooking a dense park through which flows calmly a small ravine, or a run, as we like to call it in this part of the world.
There isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly much to see here, the telescope being in outer Space and all that, but there is a friendly cafeteria with large glass windows serving Central American food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Parade</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/christmas-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 14:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/christmas-parade/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m usually very reluctant to try new places. I do enjoy the places AFTER I&amp;rsquo;ve been to them, the trouble lies with the planning phase. While there are several reviews available online none of them talk about, for example, how long does it take to get to Hopkins from the place? Or how sunny does it get at 3pm on a Sunday in December? None of the reviews, in short, provide any useful information to a graduate student.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 12:40:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/fun/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>I spent the entire day today configuring Hugo so that I can write a blog. The alternative was of course using the free, efficient, easy to use, readily configurable blog sites. What be life without a little pain?
In my college I owned a shitty Acer laptop with an utterly useless battery and a cooling system so bad that the fan would act as a noise cancelling device for the din outside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siteMap</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/modules/sitemap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/modules/sitemap/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tagCloud</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/modules/tagcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/modules/tagcloud/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>