<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Non Fiction on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/non-fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Non Fiction on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/non-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/gtd-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/gtd-method/</guid>
      <description>These are some notes I took from the book Getting Things Done by David Allen. Let me first start with the cons of the book. First the book is tediously repetitive, while some repetition is good to drill the concepts deep in your mind, the book overdoes it. Second, the book is clearly intended for people who&amp;rsquo;ve white collar jobs, mostly managers and executives.
But that does not mean that you cannot gatecrash the party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Area of Darkness</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/an-area-of-darkness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/art/books/an-area-of-darkness/</guid>
      <description>An Area of Darkness is a disturbing pessimistic novel written by V.S. Naipaul about his first visit to India in 1962. This was India not too long after the Independence with it&amp;rsquo;s freshly minted Constitution, trying to make a transition from an English past to an Indian future. Naipaul shares the sentiments of West, the tone of the book is not unlike Slumdog Millionaire (a very unpopular movie in India).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking, Fast &amp; Slow</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/the-two-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 12:40:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/the-two-systems/</guid>
      <description>Thinking, Fast and Slow in a life changing book written by our lord and savior Daniel Kahneman, Danny Kanny.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read this book you should drop everything that you&amp;rsquo;re doing and start reading it right away. It is extremely well written and easy to read, with short chapters and lucid Hemingway-styled language lacking any pretentiousness.
Danny Kanny posits a two system model for our minds. The faster system which is also the system truly in charge, Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>