<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Boredom</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/boredom/</guid>
      <description>I miss being bored.
I miss the feeling of time passing too slowly; it only ever rushes past me hastily these days.
Ever since college, it seems like I&amp;rsquo;ve constantly been near a screen of some kind. In order to avoid boredom, I&amp;rsquo;ve watched innumerable series, movies, and videos, read hundreds of books but it all feels like I saw it happening from a distance. The trouble with screens is they only satisfy half of your senses, all screens smell and feel the same, so the memories you form when you are in front of one are fragmentary, incomplete, they aren&amp;rsquo;t immersive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Thyself</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/know-thyself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/know-thyself/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important lessons of Thinking, Fast and Slow is that our brains are unable to analyze real world data objectively. We alter our memories and retroactively modify our experiences to fit a story. The only solution to this is to keep records and to trust the data.
For me, the two most easily measurable resources are internet usage and money. After reading the book I was sure I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being honest with myself about these things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Dance</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/uncategorized/stray-thoughts/why-i-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/uncategorized/stray-thoughts/why-i-dance/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been spending a lot of time thinking about what I want to do with my life. Turns out this is a really hard question. The biggest difficulty is probably trying to understand what it means to do something with your life.
Right now I&amp;rsquo;m coming back from a dance meet-up with some old friends and new, a little tipsy and drinking some more, and a lot exhilarated from moving on the dance floor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>