<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Serendipity</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/serendipity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/lifejhu/serendipity/</guid>
      <description>We were sitting at the far end of the pub, tired, exhausted, and relieved. I was slowly wiping the water that had condensed on the glass of my IPA with my fingertips, or was it a Belgian? We had conjoined two adjacent tables. The pub was playing some recent-old pop music, as usual. The lights were dim and yellow, there were television screens tucked in every corner airing sports to give people something to look at between conversations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Thyself</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/know-thyself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/know-thyself/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important lessons of Thinking, Fast and Slow is that our brains are unable to analyze real world data objectively. We alter our memories and retroactively modify our experiences to fit a story. The only solution to this is to keep records and to trust the data.
For me, the two most easily measurable resources are internet usage and money. After reading the book I was sure I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being honest with myself about these things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Dance</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/stray-thoughts/why-i-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/random/stray-thoughts/why-i-dance/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been spending a lot of time thinking about what I want to do with my life. Turns out this is a really hard question. The biggest difficulty is probably trying to understand what it means to do something with your life.
Right now I&amp;rsquo;m coming back from a dance meet-up with some old friends and new, a little tipsy and drinking some more, and a lot exhilarated from moving on the dance floor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>