<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thinking Fast and Slow on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/posts/thinking-fast-and-slow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thinking Fast and Slow on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 12:40:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/posts/thinking-fast-and-slow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Attribute Substitution</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/attribute-substitution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 12:40:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/attribute-substitution/</guid>
      <description>See the preamble to this post.
The most obvious bias of Mr. System 1 is attribute substitution. As Danny Kanny puts it, we replace the hard questions which cannot be answered, by easy ones that we know the answers to thereby deceiving ourselves into believing that we&amp;rsquo;ve found the answers.
For example, when we think about whether a person is guilty in a particular crime (a very difficult question) Mr. System 1 replaces it with whether the person is well-behaved and likely to have committed the crime (an easy question), our legal system tries to mitigate the influence of Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Rational</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/being-rational/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 12:40:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/being-rational/</guid>
      <description>Thinking, Fast and Slow in a life changing book written by our lord and savior Daniel Kahneman, Danny Kanny.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read this book you should drop everything that you&amp;rsquo;re doing and start reading it right away. It is extremely well written and easy to read, with short chapters and lucid Hemingway-styled language lacking any pretentiousness. While I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to summarize the book I am bound to fail miserably as neither do I fully understand it, nor do I have the eloquence and skill necessary to undertake such an enormous writing project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>