<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Improv Journal on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/improv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Improv Journal on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/improv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Character as Game</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/improv/character-as-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/improv/character-as-game/</guid>
      <description>We talked about how it is possible to play a character that is either
 close to you, completely opposite of you.  Both are completely valid options to play. And by making choices for what character to play, the character itself can become the game in the scene.
The important thing is to make strong choices and have strong beliefs, without which the character becomes both hard to believe and unplayable as a game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VAPAPO</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/improv/vapapo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/improv/vapapo/</guid>
      <description>VAPAPO is a character creation technique created by Jill Bernard, the author of Small Cute Book of Improv. 
Voice Atittude Posture Animal Prop Obsession  The idea of VAPAPO is that by strongly choosing each of the 6 traits it is possible to create an entirely unique character in each scene. Further, these choices are indepedent of the scene and can be made beforehand thereby making a very colorful scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laban Technique</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/improv/laban/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/improv/laban/</guid>
      <description>Laban categorized human movement into four component parts:
 Space Time Weight Flow  Each of those parts has two elements:
 Space is either direct or indirect. Speed is either quick or sustained. Weight is either heavy or light. Flow is either bound or free.  In class, we mainly focused on the eight efforts.
            PUNCH Direct Quick Heavy Bound   PRESS Direct Sustained Heavy Bound   SLASH Indirect Quick Heavy Free   WRING Indirect Sustained Heavy Bound   DAB Direct Quick Light Bound   FLICK Indirect Quick Light Free   FLOAT Indirect Sustained Light Free   GLIDE Direct Sustained Light Free    Reference: https://somersetacademy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commedia dell&#39;arte</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/improv/commedia-dellarte/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/improv/commedia-dellarte/</guid>
      <description>We learnt about the various stock characters in the old Italian troupe of Comedia dell&amp;rsquo;arte. The goal is to express a character using their physical mannersisms and try and use these characteristics in your act.
 Pantalone A suspicious miser. He is always hunched over, bent head, conniving, hands hidden and close to the chest. He walks slowly . He speaks in a rough hoarse voice without every looking up. He steps toe first, with slow high soft steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viola Spolin</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/improv/viola-spolin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/improv/viola-spolin/</guid>
      <description>We played some theater games to learn how to not get self conscious while on the stage and be more aware and have a better stage presence.
 Mirroring, physical and vocal Kitty wants a spot Green light, red light Who am I? Scence on scene Animals Throwing Knives Emotional Symphony Voices
    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>