<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Me on Grad Student Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Me on Grad Student Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy of Running</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/joy-of-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/joy-of-running/</guid>
      <description>The running high is like having a prolonged orgasm.
I have a love-hate relationship with running. At the core of it, it is an extremely repetitive act, you&amp;rsquo;re doing one thing and one thing only, but then it is this simplicity of action that puts you in a trance. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, the time before you start running and the time at the beginning of the run is excruciating, there is just no rational reason to subject yourself to such a monotonous ordeal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boredom</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/boredom/</guid>
      <description>I miss being bored.
I miss the feeling of time passing too slowly; it only ever rushes past me hastily these days.
Ever since college, it seems like I&amp;rsquo;ve constantly been near a screen of some kind. In order to avoid boredom, I&amp;rsquo;ve watched innumerable series, movies, and videos, read hundreds of books but it all feels like I saw it happening from a distance. The trouble with screens is they only satisfy half of your senses, all screens smell and feel the same, so the memories you form when you are in front of one are fragmentary, incomplete, they aren&amp;rsquo;t immersive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Thyself</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/know-thyself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/know-thyself/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important lessons of Thinking, Fast and Slow is that our brains are unable to analyze real world data objectively. We alter our memories and retroactively modify our experiences to fit a story. The only solution to this is to keep records and to trust the data.
For me, the two most easily measurable resources are internet usage and money. After reading the book I was sure I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being honest with myself about these things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/gtd-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/gtd-method/</guid>
      <description>These are some notes I took from the book Getting Things Done by David Allen. Let me first start with the cons of the book. First the book is tediously repetitive, while some repetition is good to drill the concepts deep in your mind, the book overdoes it. Second, the book is clearly intended for people who&amp;rsquo;ve white collar jobs, mostly managers and executives.
But that does not mean that you cannot gatecrash the party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking, Fast &amp; Slow</title>
      <link>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/the-two-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 12:40:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvnakade.github.io/blog/journal/me/the-two-systems/</guid>
      <description>Thinking, Fast and Slow in a life changing book written by our lord and savior Daniel Kahneman, Danny Kanny.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read this book you should drop everything that you&amp;rsquo;re doing and start reading it right away. It is extremely well written and easy to read, with short chapters and lucid Hemingway-styled language lacking any pretentiousness.
Danny Kanny posits a two system model for our minds. The faster system which is also the system truly in charge, Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>